<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tan Duc Mai</title>
    <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tan Duc Mai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 05:36:31 +1030</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Naming Conventions</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/python-naming-conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 05:36:31 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/python-naming-conventions/</guid>
      <description>An Introduction to Clean Code in Python Although you are allowed to make up your own names for variables,you must follow these rules:
  You cannot use one of Python&amp;rsquo;s keywords as a variable name.
  A variable name cannot contain spaces.
  The first character must be one of the letters a..z, A..Z, or an underscore character ( __ ).
  After the first character, you may use the letters a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Validator</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/projects/credit-card-validator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/projects/credit-card-validator/</guid>
      <description>→ GitHub Introduction Chances are you have a credit card in your wallet or purse. Credit card numbers have a &amp;lsquo;checksum&amp;rsquo; built into them, a mathematical relationship between at least one number and the others. The checksum enables a computer to detect typos, if not fraudulent numbers, without having to query a database (which can be slow). Most cards use an algorithm invented by Hans Peter Luhn, a scientist who worked for IBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackjack</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/projects/blackjack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/projects/blackjack/</guid>
      <description>→ GitHub Introduction In a standard game of 2-player Blackjack the player and the dealer are dealt 2 cards. The player shows both cards face-up. The dealer shows one of their cards face-up and one face-down. The player decides to draw cards by saying, &amp;ldquo;hit&amp;rdquo;, or stop drawing cards by saying, &amp;ldquo;stand&amp;rdquo;. They will draw cards trying to get their total hand value as close to 21 as possible without going over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petals Around The Rose</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/projects/petals-around-the-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/projects/petals-around-the-rose/</guid>
      <description>→ GitHub Introduction The name of the game is Petals Around the Rose and the name of the game is important. The computer will roll five dice and ask the user to guess the score for the roll. The score will always be an even number (including zero). The user’s mission is to work out how the computer calculates the score in order to become a Potentate of the Rose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Features Of CoderPortfolio</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/featuresofcoderportfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/featuresofcoderportfolio/</guid>
      <description>Change Point &amp;ldquo;private content&amp;rdquo; short code added. It is now possible to communicate your personal hobby and your own content.
You can use it easily. Please see &amp;ldquo;theme-demo&amp;rdquo; for details and demo.
An animation of red underline was added to Anchor. The site became a little fun and colorful.
The button of the SNS share was added. It became to have an influence when writing articles more.
Changed the color scheme of code highlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme Demo</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/theme-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/theme-demo/</guid>
      <description>Style Demo h1 Heading h2 Heading h3 Heading h4 Heading h5 Heading h6 Heading  This is bold text
This is bold text
This is italic text
This is italic text
Deleted text
This is text with inline math $\sum_{n=1}^{\infty} 2^{-n} = 1$ and with math blocks:
$$ \sum_{n=1}^{\infty} 2^{-n} = 1 $$
   Heading Another heading     text text   text text   text text     Block quotes are written like so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/hugo-template-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/hugo-template-primer/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Goto hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your os and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at installing hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>I have just obtained a Diploma of Information Technology at Eynesbury Institute of Business and Technology (EIBT) and am currently taking an Undergraduate degree in Networking and Cybersecurity at the University of South Australia (UniSA).
 Have a strong Maths background, some programming languages (especially Python), LAN (switching, routing) and rerouting knowledge. Passionate about maximising working outcomes. Confident in working collaboratively through past work experience. Actively seek an internship with opportunity growth and a learning potential that reinforces my technical knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blissful-mayer-90b8fc.netlify.app/contact/</guid>
      <description>Want Contact? Have questions or suggestions? Feel free to open an issue on GitHub or ask me on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>