<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>network on Tan Duc Mai</title>
    <link>https://tanducmai.com/categories/network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in network on Tan Duc Mai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 01:06:11 +0930</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanducmai.com/categories/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LANs and WANs</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/posts/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/lans-and-wans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 01:06:11 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/posts/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/lans-and-wans/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Types of Networks Local Area Networks Wide Area Networks </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - Components</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/posts/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/network-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 23:07:50 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/posts/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/network-components/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Overview End Devices  Examples   Intermediary Network Devices  Examples Functions   Network Media Other Terminologies Topology Diagrams  Overview The path that a message takes from source to destination can be as simple as a single cable connecting one computer to another, or as complex as a collection of networks that literally spans the globe. This network infrastructure provides the stable and reliable channel over which these communications occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - Provide Resources</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/posts/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/provide-resources-in-a-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 20:54:40 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/posts/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/provide-resources-in-a-network/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Network of Many Sizes  Small Home Networks Small Office/Home Office (SOHO) Networks Medium to Large Networks World Wide Networks   Clients and Servers  Host Roles Servers Clients Examples   Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Networking  Network of Many Sizes Networks come in all sizes, ranging from simple networks consisting of two computers to complex ones connecting millions of devices.
Small Home Networks connect a few computers to one another and to the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>