<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>network on Tan Duc Mai</title>
    <link>https://tanducmai.com/categories/network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in network on Tan Duc Mai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 23:27:09 +0930</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanducmai.com/categories/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - Data Transfer</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/network-protocols-and-communications/network-data-transfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 23:27:09 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/network-protocols-and-communications/network-data-transfer/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Message Segmentation  Advantages Disadvantages   Protocol Data Units (PDU) Sending and Receiving Process  Sending a Message Receiving a Message   Encapsulation Example Network Addresses and Data Link Addresses  Layer 3 Logical Addresses Layer 2 Physical Addresses    Message Segmentation In theory, a single communication, such as a music video or an email message, could be sent across a network from a source to a destination as one massive, uninterrupted stream of bits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - Layered Model</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/network-protocols-and-communications/network-layered-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 21:42:13 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/network-protocols-and-communications/network-layered-model/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Benefits of Using Layered Models The OSI Reference Model  Layers Communication Process   The TCP/IP Protocol Model  Layers Communication Process   Model Comparision  Benefits of Using Layered Models The benefits to using a layered model to describe network protocols and operations include:
 Assisting in protocol design because protocols that operate at a specific layer have defined information that they act upon and a defined interface to the layers above and below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - Protocols</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/network-protocols-and-communications/network-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:32:44 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/network-protocols-and-communications/network-protocols/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Protocols  Protocol Suite Protocol Stack Network Protocols   Protocol Interaction  HTTP TCP IP Ethernet   Communication Process  Protocols rules that govern communications.  Protocols define standardised formats for data packets, techniques for detecting and correcting errors, and so on.
Protocol Suite a set of protocols that work together to provide comprehensive network communication services.  Protocol suites are implemented by hosts and networking devices in software, hardware, or both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - Rules of Communication</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/network-protocols-and-communications/network-rules-of-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:19:48 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/network-protocols-and-communications/network-rules-of-communication/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Communication Fundamentals Rule Establishment Message Encoding Message Formatting and Encapsulation Message Size Message Timing  Access Method Flow Control Response Timeout   Message Delivery Options  Unicast (one-to-one) Multicast (one-to-many) Broadcast (one-to-all)    Communication Fundamentals A network can be as complex as devices connected across the Internet, or as simple as two computers directly connected to one another with a single cable, and anything in-between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - Architecture</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/network-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 15:28:52 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/network-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Network Architecture Fault Tolerance Scalability Quality of Service Security Network Architecture Requirements  Network Architecture the technologies that support the infrastructure and the programmed services and rules, or protocols, that move data across the network.  Networks must support a wide range of applications and services, as well as operate over many different types of cables and devices, which make up the physical infrastructure.
There are four basic characteristics that the underlying architectures need to address in order to meet user expectations:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - LANs, WANs, and the Internet</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/network-lans-wans-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 01:06:11 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/network-lans-wans-internet/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Network Infrastructure  Common Types Other Types   Local Area Networks Wide Area Networks The Internet Intranets and Extranets Internet Access Technologies Home and Small Office Internet Connections Businesses Internet Connections  Network Infrastructure Network infrastructures can vary greatly in terms of:
 Size of the area covered Number of users connected Number and types of services available Area of responsibility  Common Types  Local Area Network (LAN) - provides access to users and end devices in a small geographical area, which is typically an enterprise, home, or small business network owned and managed by an individual or IT department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - Components</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/network-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 23:07:50 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/network-components/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Overview End Devices  Examples   Intermediary Network Devices  Examples Functions   Network Media Other Terminologies Topology Diagrams  Overview The path that a message takes from source to destination can be as simple as a single cable connecting one computer to another, or as complex as a collection of networks that literally spans the globe. This network infrastructure provides the stable and reliable channel over which these communications occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network - Provide Resources</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/provide-resources-in-a-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 20:54:40 +0930</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/blog/network/introduction-to-networks/explore-the-network/provide-resources-in-a-network/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Network of Many Sizes  Small Home Networks Small Office/Home Office (SOHO) Networks Medium to Large Networks World Wide Networks   Clients and Servers  Host Roles Servers Clients Examples   Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Networking  Network of Many Sizes Networks come in all sizes, ranging from simple networks consisting of two computers to complex ones connecting millions of devices.
Small Home Networks connect a few computers to one another and to the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>