<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>turtle on Tan Duc Mai</title>
    <link>https://tanducmai.com/tags/turtle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in turtle on Tan Duc Mai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanducmai.com/tags/turtle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Petals Around The Rose</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/projects/petals-around-the-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/projects/petals-around-the-rose/</guid>
      <description>→ GitHub Table of Contents  Aim Introduction Further Research Sample Output  Aim Write a Pytram that allows a user to play a game called Petals Around the Rose. The program allows the user to repeatedly guess the answer to the puzzle until the user chooses to stop guessing/playing. Once the user chooses to stop guessing, the program will report the user’s and game play statistics to the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar System Turtle Graphics</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/projects/solar-system-turtle-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/projects/solar-system-turtle-graphics/</guid>
      <description>→ GitHub Table of Contents  Aim Implementation Output Video Production  Aim Use Turtle graphics to draw an illustration of the Solar System, with appropriate scaling.
Implementation There are two algorithms that I constantly use when working with a Python Turtle project, which is making a turtle and moving it. Accordingly, I define the two functions to eliminate repetitive code and put them into a new Python file. This is to make it possible to break up such a large program into manageable sized parts, and to keep related parts together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympic Medals Turtle Graphics</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/projects/olympic-medals-turtle-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/projects/olympic-medals-turtle-graphics/</guid>
      <description>→ GitHub Table of Contents  Aim Leaderboard Implementation Output Video Production  Aim Use Turtle graphics (turtle module) to draw a pie chart representing the share of gold medals at the Olympic Games Tokyo as of 2 August 2021.
Leaderboard Source: Adelaide Advertiser 3 August 2021
Implementation To begin, I convert the numbers of gold medals into percentages in order to draw the pie chart’s segments. The corresponding percentage is converted by dividing the number of gold medals by 360%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Life Turtle Graphics</title>
      <link>https://tanducmai.com/projects/city-life-turtle-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanducmai.com/projects/city-life-turtle-graphics/</guid>
      <description>→ GitHub Table of Contents  Aim Implementation Output Video Production  Aim Use Turtle graphics (turtle module) to draw an illustration of the city life, with house, car, animal, and so on.
Implementation To begin, I import the turtle module, after which I define all of the functions I am going to use in the code. I then set the window for the project by setting the height and width.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>